Guide to the Duke Family New York Apartments Collection, 1908-1997 RL.01435
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- New York Apartment (475 Park Avenue, Penthouse B), 1965-1997
  - Administrative Records, 1965-1997
    - Invoices and vouchers relating to lighting repairs at the NY Apartment. 1968, 1980–1982 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Financial statements of the 475 Park Avenue Corporation. 1969, 1972, 1974 (copies), 1975–1982 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Requisition for repair of a tiger rug stored in the Duke Farms Fur Vault. Rug came from the NY Apartment (1981). File also includes invoice and notes relating to the restoration of 3 silk rugs from the NY Apartment and the cleaning of 2 silk rugs. 1969, 1971, 1981, 1988, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Compiled list of bills for the cleaning of window treatments and the purchase of fabrics and labor costs for the NY Apartment. Certain materials contain materials designated for other locations (Rough Point). 1971 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Invoices and related materials concerning purchases made for the NY Apartment. 1971–1977 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Invoices for furniture and fixtures purchased for the NY Apartment. 1971, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Invoices and vouchers for artwork purchased for the NY Apartment and conservation work on paintings. 1972, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Invoices and vouchers relating to electrical repairs performed at the NY Apartment. 1980–1983 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Estimate for repair and refinishing of hardwood floors in the Living Room of the NY Apartment. 1982 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Invoice relating to renovations made to Doris Duke’s dressing area fabric walls in the NY Apartment. 1984 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Invoices and related materials concerning the small refrigerator a the NY Apartment. 1989 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Financial statements of the 475 Park Avenue Corporation (1991–December 31, 1992). 1993 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Financial statements of the 475 Park Avenue Corporation (1993–December 31, 1994, 1995–1996). 1995, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Acceptance of Assignment and Assumption of Lease signed by Doris Duke. Lease of NY Apartment assigned to David Rimmer. 1965 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Real estate application, acceptance of Assignment and Assumption of Lease by Doris Duke, and related correspondence concerning Doris Duke’s purchase of the NY Apartment, through David Rimmer, from Julius Stulman. 1965 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Notice of Annual Meeting of Shareholders, 475 Park Ave. Corporation. May 8, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Meeting notices, announcements, and related memoranda concerning the shareholders of the 475 Park Avenue Corporation. 1975–1983, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Contract for a burglar alarm service for the New York Apartment. 1981 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Checklist, handwritten, containing specific items in the collection of the NY Apartment. File also includes notes, and a list of items at Duke Farms. n.d. (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Inventory, maintenance report, NY Apartment. 1977–1983 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Inventory cards and photos (copies) of pieces at the NY Apartment. 1989 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Inventory, NY Apartment (475 Park Ave., PH-B), 1988–1989 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Copy of photos of 6 Haitian paintings moved from Beverly Hills to the NY Apartment. Original photos housed in Photo Collection, PH.NYA001. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Architectural Records, 1965-1983
    Approximately 10 items
    Includes the original floor plan for Penthouse B as a sales brochure from the realtors Douglas L. Elliman & Co. and two Diazo prints of proposed alterations to the Penthouse apartment.
    Digital use copies exist for two of the architectural records and have been identified below. Digital use copies can only be accessed onsite in the Rubenstein Library Reading Room. To request access please contact Research Services prior to visiting the library.
    - New York Apartment (475 Park Avenue, Penthouse B)
      - Floor Plans, & Misc. Details, Drawing No. A-1. Gerhard E. Karplus, architect. 1965 Oct 4. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D8F11)
      - Revised Floor Plan, Drawing No. A-1A. Gerhard E. Karplus, architect. 1966 Jan 28. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D8F11)
        Digital use copy is available in the Reading Room
      - [Mr. Tirella's Sketch, Bedroom/Bath]. 1966 Jan 18. Diazo. (Oversize-folder C1D8F11)
      - Part Floor Plan, 475 Park Avenue. W.F. Chun, architect. 1983 Jun 17. Photocopy. (Oversize-folder C1D8F11)
      - Alternate Scheme, 475 Park Avenue. W.F. Chun, architect. 1983 Jul 8. Photocopy. (Oversize-folder C1D8F11)
      - Penthouse B, Shreve, Lamb & Harmon Associates, 1965 (Oversize-folder C1D8F11)